<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Opinion on speculatio pauperis in deserto</title>
    <link>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/tags/opinion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Opinion on speculatio pauperis in deserto</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 08:29:12 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/tags/opinion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Best Picture nominees, ranked</title>
      <link>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/posts/2024/0310_oscars/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 08:29:12 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/posts/2024/0310_oscars/</guid>
      <description>Here I rank the Oscars nominees for Best Picture, from least favorite to favorite. Honestly this was a very good year for Best Picture nominees so it was hard ranking them. With the exception of my bottom 3 (I really did not care for any of those), I could very easily arrive at an entirely different ranking, depending on the day.&#xA;10. Maestro Everything about Bradley Cooper&amp;rsquo;s Leonard Bernstein biopic just felt so effortful, especially the performances.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Frequent &amp; spontaneous blessing</title>
      <link>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/posts/2023/1229_frequent-spontaneous-blessing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Dec 2023 11:24:32 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/posts/2023/1229_frequent-spontaneous-blessing/</guid>
      <description>Fiducia supplicans presents itself as &amp;ldquo;an innovative contribution to the pastoral meaning of blessings, permitting a broadening &amp;amp; enrichment of the classical understanding of blessings&amp;rdquo; (emphasis original). I have already said something about how this &amp;ldquo;innovation&amp;rdquo; might fit into a Catholic theological project, particularly where doctrinal development is concerned. I&amp;rsquo;d like now to comment more broadly on the document itself &amp;amp; what it has to say about blessings of couples. My main takeaway from Fiducia supplicans is that all persons &amp;amp; couples, including but not only those couples whose relationships do not conform to the church&amp;rsquo;s expectations, stand in need of God&amp;rsquo;s love &amp;amp; mercy, &amp;amp; so spontaneous, frequent, &amp;amp; abundant blessing of all persons &amp;amp; couples ought to be a regular feature of the church&amp;rsquo;s life as &amp;ldquo;sacrament of God&amp;rsquo;s infinite love&amp;rdquo; (§43).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why do we need the humanities if no one is majoring in them?</title>
      <link>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/posts/20231228_why-do-we-need-the-humanities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 08:24:37 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/posts/20231228_why-do-we-need-the-humanities/</guid>
      <description>Clarkson University announces plan to phase out majors in humanities, communications.&#xA;[Kelly] Chezum [Clarkson&amp;rsquo;s vice president for external relations] said the university has always been focused on STEM (science, technology, engineering and mathematics). The nine majors being phased out — social documentation, history, literature, sociology, film, political science, digital arts and sciences, communications and media, and interdisciplinary liberal studies and humanities — represent less than 2% of students.&#xA;Very often when programs in the humanities are cut, the cuts are justified&amp;mdash;explicitly or not&amp;mdash;by pointing out how few students will be affected by these cuts.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
