<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Teaching on speculatio pauperis in deserto</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/teaching/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Teaching on speculatio pauperis in deserto</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 16:11:29 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Three things no. 2</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/1005_three-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2024 16:11:29 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/1005_three-things/</guid>
      <description>The early Franciscans refusing to handle coin yet begging for alms, the new Joker movie, &amp;amp; the new Nosferatu trailer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three things no. 1</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/0928_three-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2024 10:05:02 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/0928_three-things/</guid>
      <description>Blogging, RSS, &amp;amp; a writing lab</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First things first</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/0115_first-things-first/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2024 11:05:29 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2024/0115_first-things-first/</guid>
      <description>One of the particular challenges of teaching theology today&amp;mdash;even to students who have some religious background&amp;mdash;is the utter lack of theological formation most people in the United States receive. Some students may come in with some religious formation, in that they have participated in their church&amp;rsquo;s faith formation classes or even theology classes in a religious high school, but that formation tends to be more catechetical than theological. To oversimplify, catechesis provides a student with a religious community&amp;rsquo;s answers to theological questions, but it does not always provide the rationale for those answers.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why do we need the humanities if no one is majoring in them?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/20231228_why-do-we-need-the-humanities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2023 08:24:37 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/20231228_why-do-we-need-the-humanities/</guid>
      <description>Clarkson University announces plan to phase out majors in humanities, communications.&#xA;[Kelly] Chezum [Clarkson&amp;rsquo;s vice president for external relations] said the university has always been focused on STEM (science, technology, engineering and mathematics). The nine majors being phased out — social documentation, history, literature, sociology, film, political science, digital arts and sciences, communications and media, and interdisciplinary liberal studies and humanities — represent less than 2% of students.&#xA;Very often when programs in the humanities are cut, the cuts are justified&amp;mdash;explicitly or not&amp;mdash;by pointing out how few students will be affected by these cuts.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Writing assignments in Theology 101</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/20230903_writing-assignments-in-theology-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 14:36:55 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/20230903_writing-assignments-in-theology-101/</guid>
      <description>(Well, not quite Theology 101; rather, Theology &amp;amp; Franciscan Studies 101, which isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly an intro to theology.)&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m finally getting close to a &amp;ldquo;final form&amp;rdquo; for my sections of &amp;ldquo;The Way of Francis &amp;amp; Clare.” The course schedule, including reading assignments, is mostly set, but what&amp;rsquo;s really tied together the entire course is the integration of a service learning project throughout the semester.&#xA;Throughout the semester, students take what they learn about Franciscan values to design, plan, &amp;amp; implement a service project that does some good for the local community.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On teaching Francis &amp; Clare</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/20230623_on-teaching-francis-clare/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 09:08:58 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/20230623_on-teaching-francis-clare/</guid>
      <description>How to teach a course on Francis &amp;amp; Clare of Assisi?1 The 101 class offered by the Department of Theology &amp;amp; Franciscan Studies at St. Bonaventure University is titled “The Way of Francis &amp;amp; Clare.” This course aims to introduce students to the Franciscan roots that underlie the mission &amp;amp; values of SBU by a semester-long study of the lives &amp;amp; writings of Francis &amp;amp; Clare.&#xA;Teaching such a course is not without its challenges.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
