<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reflection on speculatio pauperis in deserto</title>
    <link>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/tags/reflection/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reflection on speculatio pauperis in deserto</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 08:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/tags/reflection/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A new blog</title>
      <link>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/posts/20231227_a-new-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 08:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/posts/20231227_a-new-blog/</guid>
      <description>When I started micro blogging in 2021, I never planned to do anything but that: micro blog. I&amp;rsquo;d tried to blog before&amp;mdash;my first website was a static site generated by Jekyll&amp;mdash;but it had never stuck. I liked the idea of instead having a fairly low-effort, ephemeral site: a blog populated with posts about what I&amp;rsquo;m reading, quotations I&amp;rsquo;m mulling over, even some pictures, etc. For a while that&amp;rsquo;s all I did with micro.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing assignments in Theology 101</title>
      <link>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/posts/20230903_writing-assignments-in-theology-101/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2023 14:36:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/posts/20230903_writing-assignments-in-theology-101/</guid>
      <description>(Well, not quite Theology 101; rather, Theology &amp;amp; Franciscan Studies 101, which isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly an intro to theology.)
I&amp;rsquo;m finally getting close to a &amp;ldquo;final form&amp;rdquo; for my sections of &amp;ldquo;The Way of Francis &amp;amp; Clare.” The course schedule, including reading assignments, is mostly set, but what&amp;rsquo;s really tied together the entire course is the integration of a service learning project throughout the semester.
Throughout the semester, students take what they learn about Franciscan values to design, plan, &amp;amp; implement a service project that does some good for the local community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On teaching Francis &amp; Clare</title>
      <link>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/posts/20230623_on-teaching-francis-clare/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Jun 2023 09:08:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/posts/20230623_on-teaching-francis-clare/</guid>
      <description>How to teach a course on Francis &amp;amp; Clare of Assisi?1 The 101 class offered by the Department of Theology &amp;amp; Franciscan Studies at St. Bonaventure University is titled “The Way of Francis &amp;amp; Clare.” This course aims to introduce students to the Franciscan roots that underlie the mission &amp;amp; values of SBU by a semester-long study of the lives &amp;amp; writings of Francis &amp;amp; Clare.
Teaching such a course is not without its challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A few things you would read if you wanted to figure out what I get out of christianity</title>
      <link>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/posts/20230410_a-few-things-you-would-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 14:30:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/posts/20230410_a-few-things-you-would-read/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by Phil Christman&amp;rsquo;s recent post of the same name, here&amp;rsquo;s a list of a few things you would read if you wanted to figure out what I get out of Christianity.
Here&amp;rsquo;s Christman&amp;rsquo;s own disclaimer regarding his list, which I also make for my own:
 This is not, by the way, a canon or an attempt at canon-making. It’s extremely personal, and reflects my personal circumstances, which are narrow, like everyone’s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading in 2022</title>
      <link>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/posts/20221231_reading-in-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 14:17:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/posts/20221231_reading-in-2022/</guid>
      <description>This year I read 63 books (actually a couple more, as there were some I didn&amp;rsquo;t log), &amp;amp; I tracked my reading with StoryGraph. This graph is so interesting; you can see the effect the fall &amp;amp; spring semesters have on my reading.
Some of the more engaging books I read this year include:
 Transforming Fire: Imagining Christian Teaching. Mark D. Jordan. The Argonauts. Maggie Nelson. How to Be Normal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A personal canon (in progress)</title>
      <link>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/posts/20220530_personal-canon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 14:15:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/posts/20220530_personal-canon/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I saw a tweet floating around asking for your &amp;ldquo;personal canon,&amp;rdquo; that is, which are the books that you have used to understand the world? Limiting myself only to written works (and not, say, music or film), here&amp;rsquo;s what I would say, roughly ordered according to when I encountered these books:
 The gospel according to Luke The book of Revelation A Wizard of Earthsea by Ursula K. Le Guin A Christmas Carol by Charles Dickens Les Misérables by Victor Hugo Conjectures of a Guilty Bystander by Thomas Merton Proslogion by Anselm of Canterbury The Plague by Albert Camus The Prophets by Abraham J.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
