<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Christology on speculatio pauperis in deserto</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/christology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Christology on speculatio pauperis in deserto</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 17:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/christology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Venerable night: brilliant &amp; solemn</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/20231204_venerable-night/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 17:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/20231204_venerable-night/</guid>
      <description>It was winter in Italy, eight hundred years ago, &amp;amp; Assisi’s poverello had an idea.1 Francis of Assisi had become obsessed with the words &amp;amp; deeds of Jesus Christ, his rustic parables &amp;amp; simple gestures that, despite (or perhaps because of) their lowliness, communicated divine majesty &amp;amp; awe. According to an early biographer,2 “so thoroughly did the humility of the incarnation &amp;amp; the charity of the passion occupy his memory that he scarcely wanted to think of anything else.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reading Anselm</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/20230614_reading-anselm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 14:33:33 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/20230614_reading-anselm/</guid>
      <description>I admire the aim in Elizabeth Johnson&amp;rsquo;s Creation and the Cross: The Mercy of God for a Planet in Peril: to produce a theology that considers how Jesus&amp;rsquo;s life, death, &amp;amp; resurrection are good news for the whole cosmos, particularly in the context of ecological crisis. &amp;amp; while I don&amp;rsquo;t disagree with some of the conclusions (presented chiefly in book 6), ironically the particularity of Jesus&amp;rsquo;s life (natal &amp;amp; risen) &amp;amp; his death don&amp;rsquo;t seem to determine the conclusions as much as the work&amp;rsquo;s title might lead one to expect.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Love restores the world to order</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/20230423_love-restores-the-world-to-order/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 14:32:17 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/20230423_love-restores-the-world-to-order/</guid>
      <description>Walter Kasper on kingdom of God:&#xA;But when the ultimate source of all reality, God&amp;rsquo;s love, re-establishes itself and comes to power, the world is restored to order and salvation. Because each individual can feel himself accepted and approved without reserve, he becomes free to live with others. The coming of the Kingdom of God&amp;rsquo;s love therefore means the salvation of the world as a whole and the salvation of every individual.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
