<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on speculatio pauperis in deserto</title>
    <link>http://example.org/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on speculatio pauperis in deserto</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 11:33:05 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://example.org/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>20231223_fiducia Supplicans Church Teaching</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/20231223_fiducia-supplicans-church-teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Dec 2023 11:33:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/20231223_fiducia-supplicans-church-teaching/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve seen a fair amount of hand wringing over Fiducia supplicans where the consistency of church teaching &amp;amp; papal authority are concerned. The concern goes something like this: Pope Francis, while reaffirming the Catholic church&amp;rsquo;s historical teaching on marriage (as possible only between a woman &amp;amp; a man), has allowed for the blessing of a same-sex couple (but not their relationship). This means the Catholic church will have to either forge ahead, perhaps revising its understanding of marriage to include same-sex unions, or pull back from Fiducia supplicans to reaffirm its historical understanding of marriage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Venerable night: brilliant &amp; solemn</title>
      <link>http://example.org/posts/20231204_venerable-night/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2023 17:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/posts/20231204_venerable-night/</guid>
      <description>It was winter in Italy, eight hundred years ago, &amp;amp; Assisi’s poverello had an idea.1 Francis of Assisi had become obsessed with the words &amp;amp; deeds of Jesus Christ, his rustic parables &amp;amp; simple gestures that, despite (or perhaps because of) their lowliness, communicated divine majesty &amp;amp; awe. According to an early biographer,2 “so thoroughly did the humility of the incarnation &amp;amp; the charity of the passion occupy his memory that he scarcely wanted to think of anything else.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
