<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Pages on speculatio pauperis in deserto</title>
    <link>http://example.org/pages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Pages on speculatio pauperis in deserto</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://example.org/pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>http://example.org/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi&amp;mdash;I’m Andrew Belfield, &amp;amp; I’m an assistant professor of theology &amp;amp; Franciscan studies at St. Bonaventure University. I think of this blog as an online record of what I’m reading, what I’m thinking about, &amp;amp; what I’m seeing: somewhere between a commonplace book, a journal, &amp;amp; a scrapbook, I suppose.
I take the title of this blog from the Itinerarium mentis in deum, a guidebook for union with God written by one of the great medieval theologians of the Franciscan order, Bonaventure of Bagnoregio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about my research</title>
      <link>http://example.org/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/research/</guid>
      <description>My research specialties include medieval theology (particularly early mendicant theologies) &amp;amp; christology. I also have research interests in soteriology, poverty, apocalypticism (medieval &amp;amp; contemporary), &amp;amp; trinitarian theology.

I’m currently preparing for publication a monograph on the christology of the Summa halensis, a collaborative work of the Franciscans at the University of Paris during the early 1240s. In this book, tentatively titled Christ the Penitent: The Early Franciscans &amp;amp; Scholastic Theology, I intend to show how the fratres developed what I have come to call a ‘penitential christology’: Christ makes satisfaction for sin not by dying, but by feeling contrition at human sin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>about my teaching</title>
      <link>http://example.org/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://example.org/teaching/</guid>
      <description>To study theology is to ask questions about God &amp;amp; things pertaining to God, &amp;amp; to think critically about possible answers. Students of theology don’t do this unaided; in the archive that is the history of Christian theology sits an enormous catalog of methods, questions, approaches, answers, &amp;amp; discussions from a diversity of thinkers, traditions, &amp;amp; communities.

My teaching aims, in part, to show students how to explore that archive &amp;amp; put its materials to use as they navigate these fundamental questions of human existence &amp;amp; divine reality.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
