<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>reading on speculatio pauperis in deserto</title>
    <link>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/tags/reading/</link>
    <description>Recent content in reading on speculatio pauperis in deserto</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 10:18:10 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/tags/reading/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Logbook—December 2023</title>
      <link>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/posts/2023/1231_logbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 10:18:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/posts/2023/1231_logbook/</guid>
      <description>In which I read Bullshit Jobs: A Theory &amp;amp; Swimming in the Dark &amp;amp; Silence: A Novel &amp;amp; Way Back to God: The Spiritual Theology of St Bonaventure &amp;amp; Doppleganger: A Trip into the Mirror World; &amp;amp; watched The Grapes of Wrath &amp;amp; May December &amp;amp; The Holdovers &amp;amp; The Hunger Games: The Ballad of Songbirds &amp;amp; Snakes &amp;amp; Napoleon &amp;amp; The Muppets Christmas Carol &amp;amp; Home Alone &amp;amp; Poor Things &amp;amp; It&amp;rsquo;s a Wonderful Life &amp;amp; Saltburn &amp;amp; The Color Purple (2023).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>November 2023 logbook</title>
      <link>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/posts/20231130_logbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Nov 2023 00:38:35 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/posts/20231130_logbook/</guid>
      <description>In which I watched Killers of the Flower Moon, The Blair Witch Project, &amp;amp; The Killing of a Sacred Deer; &amp;amp; read Questioning God, Ways of Seeing, Revelations of Divine Love, &amp;amp; Julian of Norwich, Theologian.
Killers of the Flower Moon (Martin Scorsese, 2023). What an amazing film. I don&amp;rsquo;t even want to say much about it here, because I know I can&amp;rsquo;t do it justice in the space of a short paragraph.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October 2023 logbook</title>
      <link>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/posts/20231031_logbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 00:40:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/posts/20231031_logbook/</guid>
      <description>I thought it might be fun at the end of each month to list the movies I&amp;rsquo;d seen that month &amp;amp; some thoughts about each.
Rope (Alfred Hitchcock, 1948). Jacqueline &amp;amp; I decided to watch some Hitchcock in honor of Halloween at the end of the month. We&amp;rsquo;ve seen a few Hitchcock already, but not Rope. I enjoyed it, though it&amp;rsquo;s not my favorite of his (that remains Psycho). I love good, long scenes, &amp;amp; Hitchcock&amp;rsquo;s clever camera work to make the entire film seem like a single take really ratchets up the tension.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading Anselm</title>
      <link>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/posts/20230614_reading-anselm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 14:33:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/posts/20230614_reading-anselm/</guid>
      <description>I admire the aim in Elizabeth Johnson&amp;rsquo;s Creation and the Cross: The Mercy of God for a Planet in Peril: to produce a theology that considers how Jesus&amp;rsquo;s life, death, &amp;amp; resurrection are good news for the whole cosmos, particularly in the context of ecological crisis. &amp;amp; while I don&amp;rsquo;t disagree with some of the conclusions (presented chiefly in book 6), ironically the particularity of Jesus&amp;rsquo;s life (natal &amp;amp; risen) &amp;amp; his death don&amp;rsquo;t seem to determine the conclusions as much as the work&amp;rsquo;s title might lead one to expect.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A few things you would read if you wanted to figure out what I get out of christianity</title>
      <link>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/posts/20230410_a-few-things-you-would-read/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 14:30:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/posts/20230410_a-few-things-you-would-read/</guid>
      <description>Inspired by Phil Christman&amp;rsquo;s recent post of the same name, here&amp;rsquo;s a list of a few things you would read if you wanted to figure out what I get out of Christianity.
Here&amp;rsquo;s Christman&amp;rsquo;s own disclaimer regarding his list, which I also make for my own:
 This is not, by the way, a canon or an attempt at canon-making. It’s extremely personal, and reflects my personal circumstances, which are narrow, like everyone’s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading in 2022</title>
      <link>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/posts/20221231_reading-in-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 14:17:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/posts/20221231_reading-in-2022/</guid>
      <description>This year I read 63 books (actually a couple more, as there were some I didn&amp;rsquo;t log), &amp;amp; I tracked my reading with StoryGraph. This graph is so interesting; you can see the effect the fall &amp;amp; spring semesters have on my reading.
Some of the more engaging books I read this year include:
 Transforming Fire: Imagining Christian Teaching. Mark D. Jordan. The Argonauts. Maggie Nelson. How to Be Normal.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A personal canon (in progress)</title>
      <link>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/posts/20220530_personal-canon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 14:15:51 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://blog.andrewbelfield.com/posts/20220530_personal-canon/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday I saw a tweet floating around asking for your &amp;ldquo;personal canon,&amp;rdquo; that is, which are the books that you have used to understand the world? Limiting myself only to written works (and not, say, music or film), here&amp;rsquo;s what I would say, roughly ordered according to when I encountered these books:
 The gospel according to Luke The book of Revelation A Wizard of Earthsea by Ursula K. Le Guin A Christmas Carol by Charles Dickens Les Misérables by Victor Hugo Conjectures of a Guilty Bystander by Thomas Merton Proslogion by Anselm of Canterbury The Plague by Albert Camus The Prophets by Abraham J.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
